- Are you ready, kids?
- 孩子们，你们准备好了吗？
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- I can't hear you.
- 我听不到你说话。
all:
Aye, aye, Captain!
全部：
是啊是啊，队长！
- ♪ Ohh... ♪
- ♪ 哦...♪
♪ Who lives in a pineapple
under the sea? ♪
♪ 谁住在菠萝里
在海底？ ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Absorbent and yellow
and porous is he ♪
- ♪ 吸水性和黄色
他是多孔的 ♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ If nautical nonsense
be something you wish ♪
- ♪ 如果航海废话
成为你想要的东西♪
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
- ♪ Then drop on the deck
and flop like a fish ♪
- ♪ 然后落在甲板上
然后像鱼一样扑通扑通♪
all: SpongeBob SquarePants!
- Ready?
所有：海绵宝宝！
- 准备好？
all:
SpongeBob SquarePants!
全部：
海绵宝宝！
SpongeBob SquarePants!
- SpongeBob
- 海绵宝宝
SquarePants!
方裤！
[laughing]
[笑]
♪ ♪
[waves crashing]
[海浪拍打]
[funky music, siren wailing]
[时髦的音乐，警报声]
♪ ♪
- Stop, thief!
- 住手，小偷！
Come back here with me formula!
带着我的配方回来吧！
[yelping]
[尖叫]
He's over there--stop him!
- [panting]
他就在那儿——拦住他！
- [气喘吁吁]
- [laughs]
I can't help it.
- [笑]
我无能为力。
I'm a kleptomaniac!
我是一个盗窃狂！
- Arr!
- 啊！
[both chomping]
[都在咀嚼]
- [laughs]
Ow!
- [笑]
噢！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- You're under arrest!
- 你被捕了！
- But I'm innocent!
- 但我是无辜的！
- No one is innocent!
- 没有人是无辜的！
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
Whoa. Things got dark fast.
哇哦。事情很快就黑了。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
♪ You're going to jail ♪
♪ 你会进监狱的 ♪
Join in the dancing, boy,
or you're fired.
加入跳舞吧，男孩，
或者你被解雇了。
♪ You're going to jail ♪
♪ 你会进监狱的 ♪
♪ You're going
to jail ♪
♪ 你要走了
进监狱♪
♪ You're going to jail ♪
♪ 你会进监狱的 ♪
- Step back, buddy.
-退后一步，伙计。
Let the law handle this.
让法律来处理这件事吧。
- Mm. Yes, officer.
- 毫米。是的，军官。
- Huh!
- And I'll be taking this!
- 哈！
- 我会接受这个！
- Wait!
That's me secret formula!
- 等待！
这就是我的秘密配方！
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
- Well, now it's evidence.
- 好吧，现在有证据了。
- [straining]
- [紧张]
- Oh.
- 哦。
- Ow!
- 噢！
- The formula!
- 公式！
I can't cook without that
formula!
没有那个我就不会做饭
公式！
[breathing heavily]
[呼吸粗重]
I can't do anything without it!
没有它我什么也做不了！
The krabby patties are gonna
taste like
蟹肉饼会
味道像
ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-ch-ch--
chum!
密友！
[all grumbling]
[大家都在抱怨]
- Wait! Don't go!
- 等待！别走！
We still have fresh buns.
我们还有新鲜的面包。
And we have air conditioning.
我们有空调。
Ohh.
哦。
Come here.
过来吧。
You and me are getting into
that police department
你和我正在进入
那个警察局
to get that formula back.
得到那个公式。
- How?
- 如何？
Ahh!
啊！
[funky music]
[时髦音乐]
♪ ♪
- By dressing like the po-po.
- 穿得像婆婆一样。
- The po-po?
Oh, no, no.
- 婆婆？
哦，不，不。
- No no po-po--
no job-o for you-o.
- 不，不，噗噗——
没有工作给你-o。
Comprendo?
理解吗？
- So so.
- 如此。
[gulps]
[吞咽]
But I'll go go.
但我还是去吧。
- Turn to your left.
- 向左转。
[camera shutter clicks]
[相机快门声]
- What is this?
- 这是什么？
- Mug shot.
- 脸部照片。
- [scoffs]
Looks nothing like me.
- [嘲笑]
看起来一点都不像我。
[yelps]
[尖叫声]
[slams]
[猛击]
- Low life.
- You'd live a low life too,
- 生命低下。
- 你也会过着低贱的生活
officer, if you were my height!
警官，如果你像我一样高就好了！
[sighs]
[叹气]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[grumbles]
[抱怨]
Hm?
嗯？
Could have given me
a bigger blanket!
可以给我
更大的毯子！
- Hm.
[soft music plays]
- 嗯。
[轻柔的音乐响起]
[hums]
- [laughs]
[哼哼]
- [笑]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
- One too many Goofy Goobers
again, eh, Patrick?
- 太多傻瓜了
再说一次，呃，帕特里克？
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
No, sir, I couldn't eat
another.
不，先生，我不能吃饭
另一个。
[unsteady moans]
[不稳定的呻吟声]
- Get in there
and sleep it off.
- 进去
然后睡一觉。
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[chuckles]
[笑声]
- [snoring]
- [打鼾]
- [snores]
- Not exactly the blanket
I wanted.
- 不完全是毯子
我想要。
- Isn't it a crime to
impersonate a police officer?
- 这不是犯罪吗
冒充警察？
- We're not impersonating,
boy-o.
- 我们不是冒充，
男孩-o。
I was in the navy, and the navy
is sort of like the cops...
我曾在海军服役，海军
有点像警察...
of the sea.
海的。
And I just deputized you.
我刚刚代理了你。
- Deput--wow!
- 副手--哇！
I always wanted to be an
officer of the law.
我一直想成为一个
法律官员。
Check it out.
I'm the fuzz.
一探究竟。
我就是毛毛
Ooh, look at this!
哦，看看这个！
I'm also a flat foot!
[giggles]
我也是扁平足！
[咯咯笑]
Watch me work.
看我工作。
[whistle chirps]
[口哨声]
Mr. Mime, you have the right
to remain silent.
米米先生，你有权利
保持沉默。
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
Stop or I'll shoot...
you a nasty look.
停下来不然我就开枪了...
你这副难看的样子。
[raspberries]
[覆盆子]
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
- [chuckles]
- [轻笑]
Huh?
啊？
Hey, let go.
嘿，放开吧。
Cops don't hold hands.
警察不拉手。
- Well...they should.
- 嗯...他们应该。
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
- Bring it in,
Officer Little Buddy.
- 把它带进来，
警官小伙伴。
- Ah!
- 啊！
[both groaning]
[两人都呻吟]
[all gasping]
[全都喘气]
- What? Cops can hug.
- 什么？警察可以拥抱。
You know, boy-o,
你知道，男孩，
we probably make some pretty
good cops.
我们可能会做一些漂亮的
好警察。
- Hm?
- 嗯？
Ohh. What have we got here?
哦。我们这里有什么？
Excuse me, miss.
对不起，小姐。
Have you got a license to sell
these cookies?
你有销售许可证吗
这些饼干？
- Officer SquarePants,
- 方裤警官，
I don't think we ought to--
我认为我们不应该——
- Let me handle this,
Officer Mr. Krabs!
- 让我来处理这件事
蟹老板先生！
Well, missy,
嗯，小姐，
do ya?
- I don't have a license.
是吗？
- 我没有执照。
- Yeah, that's what I thought.
- 是的，我就是这么想的。
You're under arrest for
violating penal code
你因以下原因被捕
违反刑法
4968973025-D.
4968973025-D。
- How did you know that?
- 你怎么知道的？
- That's classified.
- 这是机密。
- Oh, I love it here.
- 哦，我喜欢这里。
We have showers, uh,
a courtyard,
我们有淋浴，呃，
一个庭院，
and three square meals a day.
和一日三餐。
All chum... Ahh.
都是好朋友...啊。
- I know.
They're my only customer.
- 我知道。
他们是我唯一的顾客。
- [laughs]
This is the best part!
- [笑]
这是最好的部分！
[laughing]
[笑]
Pretty cool, huh?
很酷吧？
- If you attempt to use that
in front of me,
- 如果您尝试使用它
在我面前，
I'll annihilate you.
我会消灭你。
- Central booking,
also known as the cop shop.
- 中央预订，
也称为警察商店。
- How do you know these words?
- 你怎么知道这些词的？
- Still classified.
- 仍属于机密。
- Well, if it isn't little
Helen the Felon.
- 好吧，如果不是少的话
重罪犯海伦。
[slurps]
Good work, boys.
[啜饮]
干得好，孩子们。
You nabbed the most notorious
criminal in Bikini Bottom.
你抓到了最臭名昭著的人
比基尼泳裤中的罪犯。
- Huh? This sweet little thing?
- 啊？这个可爱的小东西？
- You can drop the act now,
Helen.
- 你现在可以放弃表演了
海伦.
- Ah!
- [yelps]
- 啊！
- [尖叫声]
- Yow!
- 哟！
Hey!
- [chuckles]
嘿！
- [轻笑]
That's my girl.
那是我的女孩。
All right, take her to the
interrogation room.
好吧，带她去
审讯室。
♪ ♪
- While I look for the formula,
- 当我寻找公式时，
you can interrogate
the suspect.
你可以询问
嫌疑人。
- But I don't know
how to interrogate.
- 但我不知道
如何讯问。
- Then just ask questions.
- 然后就问问题。
And act tough.
并且表现得强硬。
- Um...questions and act
tough. Got it.
- 嗯...提出问题并采取行动
艰难。知道了。
Hmm...
唔...
Okay, little Helen!
好吧，小海伦！
[inhales deeply]
[深吸一口气]
What do you think
of this weather?
你觉得怎么样
这种天气？
- I think it's wuh-vely!
- 我觉得这太棒了！
Let me ask you something.
让我问你一件事。
How long have
you been an idiot?
有多久了
你是个白痴吗？
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
[stutters]
[结巴]
I want a lawyer.
我想要一名律师。
- Just answer the question.
- 只需回答问题即可。
- [whimpers]
- [呜咽]
[gulps]
[吞咽]
[whimpers]
[呜咽]
An idiot?
白痴？
I don't know!
我不知道！
Is it hot in here?
这里热吗？
Pressure--I can't--okay,
I'll confess!
压力——我不能——好吧，
我就坦白吧！
I'll confess to it all!
我会承认这一切！
Anything! Whatever you got.
任何事物！无论你得到什么。
- [grunting]
[metal grinding]
- [咕哝]
[金属研磨]
- [sighs]
- That's it.
- [叹气]
- 就是这样。
Keep up that cacophony.
继续这种刺耳的声音。
Your noise is drowning out
my filing.
你的噪音被淹没
我的档案。
[chuckles]
[笑声]
- My stomach needs frozen
treats.
- 我的胃需要冷冻
款待。
Frozen treats.
冷冻食品。
Huh.
呵呵。
I'm gonna have to make myself
some jailhouse ice cream.
我得让自己
一些监狱冰淇淋。
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
Hmm.
唔。
Oh.
[grunts]
哦。
[咕哝]
[humming]
[嗡嗡声]
♪ ♪
Ah. [sighs]
啊。 [叹气]
[heavenly tones]
[天籁之音]
[sighs]
[叹气]
[metal grinding]
Try it!
[金属研磨]
试试吧！
You can't even tell the
difference.
你甚至无法告诉
差异。
- Blech!
- 布莱奇！
No, thanks.
不，谢谢。
But, say,
I know where they keep
但是，说吧，
我知道他们藏在哪里
the real ice cream
around here:
真正的冰淇淋
这里附近：
in the evidence room.
在证物室里。
A guy like you who knows
his way around here
像你这样懂事的人
他在这里的路
might be able--
- I have a key.
或许能够——
- 我有钥匙。
- Oh, really?
- 哦真的吗？
Let's go!
我们走吧！
- [gulps]
- [吞咽]
[hums]
[哼哼]
[grunts]
[咕哝]
[funky music]
[时髦音乐]
♪ ♪
- Donuts?
- 甜甜圈？
Whoa!
哇！
Hm.
Well...
嗯。
出色地...
Maybe just one.
也许只有一个。
[chomps]
[咀嚼]
[spits]
[吐口水]
Evidence room!
物证室！
- [moans]
- Huh?
- [呻吟]
- 啊？
You promised me ice cream!
你答应过我吃冰淇淋的！
Hmph!
哼！
- Look, once I get the secret
formula and rule the world,
- 听着，一旦我知道了秘密
公式并统治世界，
I'll buy you all the ice cream
you want!
我给你买所有的冰淇淋
你想要！
[grunts]
[咕哝]
Let's see. Comic books,
sea shells...
让我们来看看。漫画书，
海贝壳...
an old man...
一个老人...
- Hello!
- 你好！
- Outboard motors...
- 舷外发动机...
stolen jokes...
偷来的笑话...
a leg...
- My leg!
一条腿...
- 我的腿！
- Hmm?
- 唔？
Well, drop a dime on me!
There it is!
好吧，给我一毛钱吧！
就在那里！
[heavenly tones]
[chuckles]
[天籁之音]
[笑声]
- Oh, no, you don't.
- 哦，不，你不知道。
- Krabs?
What are you doing here?
- 螃蟹？
你在这里做什么？
I stole that formula
fair and square!
我偷了那个公式
公平公正！
- Well, I'm stealing it back.
- 好吧，我把它偷回来了。
- Oh, no, you're not!
- 哦，不，你不是！
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
Ooh...ooh!
噢……噢！
[boxes clatter]
[箱子碰撞声]
- Hello!
- 你好！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [groans]
- [呻吟]
- Hello!
- 你好！
- [grunts]
- [咕哝]
- [yelps]
- [尖叫声]
[clattering]
[咔哒声]
all: Hello!
全体：您好！
- Who's been pinching
all these geezers?
- 谁捏了
所有这些家伙？
- Where's my ice cream?
- 我的冰淇淋呢？
Where's my ice cream?
我的冰淇淋在哪里？
Where--
[gasps]
哪里——
[喘气]
Ohh.
哦。
Well, there it is.
嗯，就是这样。
- [groans]
- [panting]
- [呻吟]
- [气喘吁吁]
- What are you doing,
you maniac?
- 你在做什么，
你疯子？
Help! Police!
帮助！警察！
[yelping]
[尖叫]
- [yells]
- [大喊]
- What do you think you're--
- 你认为你是什么——
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
- I don't know
what you two are doing,
- 我不知道
你们两个在做什么
but it looks illegal.
但这看起来是非法的。
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
- [yells]
- [大喊]
I have a confession to make!
我有一个事要坦白！
- I'll just hold onto this
formula till the morning.
- 我会抓住这个
配方直到早上。
- Oh, but, officer,
I have more confessions.
- 哦，但是，警官，
我还有更多的忏悔。
- Zip it, kid.
- 拉上拉链，孩子。
I get it.
You're a criminal mastermind.
我得到它。
你是一个犯罪主谋。
- Guilty.
- 有罪的。
Yay!
耶！
- Hey, where's Patrick?
- 嘿，帕特里克在哪儿？
- [wails]
- [哀号]
[key clangs]
[按键叮当声]
[unsteady laughter]
[不稳定的笑声]
[sighing]
[叹气]
Oh.
哦。
[sighing]
[叹气]
[all yelp,
Patrick snores]
[大家尖叫，
帕特里克打鼾]
- Well, I must confess
this is sure cozy.
- 好吧，我必须承认
这确实很舒服。